airtricity.com 2012-06-11

# Online Privacy Policy | Greener and Cheaper Energy from Airtricity

Airtricity is the trading name of Airtricity Energy Supply (Northern Ireland) Limited and Airtricity Limited, members of the Scottish and Southern Energy Group (referred to in this privacy statement as the ‘Scottish and Southern Energy Group’ or ‘we’ or “us”).

We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This statement (together with our [terms of use](http://www.airtricity.com/ie/terms-of-use/) and any other documents referred to therein) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. 

By submitting any information, you consent to the use of that information as set out in the above documents, therefore please ensure that you read all of them carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

We will comply with the UK's Data Protection Act 1998 and the Republic of Ireland’s Data Protection Act 1988 and 2003 (as applicable) and any other locally applicable data protection legislation.

For data protection purposes, the data controller for the Scottish and Southern Energy Group is Scottish & Southern Energy plc (SC117119) having its registered address at Inveralmond House, 200 Dunkeld Road, Perth PH1 3AQ

## Information we may collect from you

We may collect and process the following data about you:

  * Information that you provide by filling in any forms on this Airtricity website (‘our website’) or any other information provided to us in writing or verbally. This may include information provided at the time of registering to use our website, subscribing to our service, posting material or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information when you report a problem with our website.
  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
  * We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.
  * Details of transactions you carry out through our website and of the fulfilment of your orders.
  * Details of your visits to our website including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access.

## IP addresses and cookies

We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

For the same reason, we may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help us to improve our website and to deliver a better and more personalised service. They enable us:

  * To estimate our audience size and usage pattern.
  * To store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customise our website according to your individual interests.
  * To speed up your searches.
  * To recognise you when you return to our website. 

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our website. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to our website.

## Where we store your personal data

We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

## Uses made of the information

We use information held about you in the following ways:

  * To ensure that content from our website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer. 
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes. 
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.
  * To notify you about changes to our service.
  * In accordance with any of our terms and conditions of supply as amended from time to time. 

We may also use your data, or permit selected third parties to use your data, to enable us to deliver goods and services to you, or to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you and we or they may contact you about these by post or telephone.

If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data (the order form).

## Disclosure of your information

Scottish and Southern Energy Group may disclose your personal information to any part of our group.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * In the event of any proposal to obtain or transfer any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective third parties to such transaction(s) and any relevant advisors.
  * If any or all our assets are obtained from or transferred to a third party, where personal data held about customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal or regulatory obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our [terms of use](http://www.airtricity.com/ie/terms-of-use/) or our [terms and conditions of supply](http://www.airtricity.com/ie/home/products/supply-of-electricity-and-or-gas/) and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of any part of the Scottish and Southern Energy Group, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.
  * In accordance with any of our terms and conditions of supply as amended from time to time [insert link to terms and conditions of supply]. 

## Your rights

You have the right to ask us to have your personal data corrected if inaccurate, or erased if we do not have a legitimate reason for retaining this. You can also ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data.  You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us [at Airtricity Limited, One Spencer Dock, North Wall Quay, Dublin 1, Ireland **OR**  [customerservice@airtricity.com](mailto:customerservice@airtricity.com)].

Our website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers, affiliates and other third parties.  If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

## Access to information

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request must be in writing, contain sufficient information to establish the identity of the Data subject and location of the information requested and a fee may be charged to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you. This fee is currently £10 in the UK and €6.35 in Ireland. All requests should be sent to the Data Protection Officer at Scottish and Southern Energy plc. Please contact us directly for more information if you wish to make such a request.

Changes to our privacy policy or your Information

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page.

If any of your information that we hold about you changes, for example if you change your name, email address or other details, please contact us and let us know.

**By submitting any information to us, you consent to the use of that information in accordance with this policy and our Terms as explained at the beginning of this policy.**
